Sayed Bin Taher

Backend Developer

🔀 sayedbintaher@gmail.com

**** 01849250564

P Dhaka, Bangladesh

13/08/1998

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sayedbin-taher-7ab096161/

PROFILE

I am an innovative and hard-working software engineer with one year of software development experience. Looking for new opportunities to grow and enhance my skills, eventually following an aspiration to be an innovative and hardworking software engineer. Flexible with my work, changing technological stack, if necessary, would not be a problem.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

BRAC University 2018 - 2022 CGPA 3.60

SKILLS

C#

Asp .Net Core, Entity Framework

SQL

MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL

Javascript

Angular, React, Typescript, jQuery

CSS/HTML

Bootstrap, Kendo UI

Tools

Git, VS Code, Visual Studio, SMSS, PgAdmin, Trello, Redmine

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

eGeneration Ltd.

Trainee Software Engineer

03/2022 - 12/2022

- Completed Training on ASP.net Core MVC, Web API and Entity Framework with 75% marks following Layered Architecture Pattern.
- Involved in creation of in-house Human Resource Management System where I contributed about 15% of the total work done in React.js.
- Generated multiple complex forms for Admin Module with frontend technology like Angular.

Raven Systems Ltd.

Junior Software Engineer 03/2023 – 07/2023

- Involved in creation of an ASP. Net Core MVC application for Directorate of Inspection of Factories and Establishment (DIFE) following Layer Architecture where I contributed about 50% of the backend application.
- Contributed to the in-house ERP system by including a small module for Support Ticket System.

TechnoNext Ltd.

Junior Software Engineer

07/2023 - present

- Utilized advanced accounting software, ShopLover Accounting, to manage financial transactions and generate comprehensive reports in the accounting project.
- Played a key role in tracking and managing land assets, including land asset purchase and sales in the US Bangla Real Estate business project.
- Worked with different DBMS like MS SQL server and PostgreSQL, and also worked with popular ORM Dapper to improve performance of overall application.

PROJECTS

Course Management System

Simple course management system with ASP .Net Core and Entity Framework.

Point of Sales Project 🛮

Point of Sales project done with ASP .Net Core Web API and Kendo UI.

Product Managment System

Product Management System with Angular 15 and ASP .Net Core Web API.